Contact

+447494332865 (Mobile) james.evans@edutechnetwork. co.uk

www.linkedin.com/in/jaevan (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Virtualization Technology Network Engineering VDI

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Microsoft Certified Professional Microsoft Lync Server 2013 Ignite Managing Office 365 Identities and Requirements

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist: Microsoft Lync Server 2010, Configuring

Microsoft Specialist: Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions

Honors-Awards

CPE Champion | Winning with Cloud Services - FY15 Q4

WW Communities | Leverage Your Communities - 2016

Director / Lead IAM Consultant working with Global Enterprises on the adoption of Microsoft Cloud Services!

United Kingdom

Summary

An enthusiastic & reliable team player with a passion for IT & service delivery. Possesses excellent organizational & project management skills enabling him to work with a client from first engagement through solution design, implementation & sign off stages.

James is seen to be well respected within the industry by corporate organizations, has worked with Microsoft on many occasions over a 5 year period prior to starting at Microsoft as an FTE in 2013.

has actively attended and contributed to the Microsoft Technical Events in the UK, and has also been contributing to and supporting the members of the largest Online Community for IT Professionals for around 8 Years.

Has worked around the globe working as the Technical Lead delivering projects for companies such as JP Morgan & Chase, Pitney Bowes, Research in Motion and Life Size.

Specialties Include:

Microsoft Azure Cloud (IaaS, PaaS and SaaS)
Microsoft Azure Active Directory (Expert in IDAM)
Microsoft Server 2003 - 2016
Microsoft Cloud Services - All Microsoft Office 365 Service
Workloads
Microsoft Communication - Exchange 2003 - 2016 / Skype 2016

Microsoft Collaboration - Exchange 2003 - 2016 / Skype 2016

Microsoft Collaboration - SharePoint 2007, 2010 & 2013

Microsoft Database - SQL Server 2008R2 & 2012

VMware ESXi & View RIM Blackberry Enterprise Server & Mobile Voice System Cisco Routing, Switches & Firewalls Watchguard. Checkpoint Firewalls

Experience

Identity Consultants Ltd Director / Lead Consultant January 2019 - Present London, United Kingdom

Deutsche Bank Microsoft Identity Management Consultant - Contract July 2019 - August 2019 (2 months) London, United Kingdom

Identity Management Consultant working in the Cloud Center of Excellence Team ensuring DB have a smooth tranistion to Microsoft Cloud and Online Services.

JTI (Japan Tobacco International)
Identity Management Consultant - Contract
December 2018 - June 2019 (7 months)
Weybridge, United Kingdom

Lead Identity Management Consultant for Global Organization. Providing Expert Consultancy on Global Microsoft Identity Management Infrastructure and Implementing Major Change Requirements. Focused on Microsoft Azure Active Directory, Azure AD Connect, MIM 2016 and GAL Sync as well as providing recommendations and expertise to kick off a global effort to improve Identity Life-cycle WW and implement Identity Governance Policies / Framework.

SPIE ICT Solutions
Microsoft Identity & Security SME & Lead Consultant - Contract
June 2018 - November 2018 (6 months)
Utrecht Area, Netherlands

Microsoft
4 years 7 months

Senior Escalation Engineer EEE-Dev

November 2015 - May 2018 (2 years 7 months)

Redmond, WA

Microsoft Azure Active Directory is a comprehensive identity and access management cloud solution that provides a robust set of capabilities to manage users and groups and help secure access to on-premises and cloud applications including Microsoft Online Services like Office 365, Microsoft Azure and a world of non-Microsoft SaaS applications.

An "Embedded" Escalation Engineer is an elite member of the Windows Serviceability Team with direct access to the Product Group in the Identity and Security Services Division (ISSD), as well as the Microsoft Online Services Hosted data center environment.

The Embedded EE Team lead engineering investigations to bring issue resolution to Support incidents impacting our customers. we also have the opportunity to directly improve the support provided to our customers via the global team of engineers who interface with customers on a day-to-day basis.

It is part of my role to Identify emerging trends or re-occurring escalation scenarios and drive engineering opportunities to mitigate and/or eliminate from the workflow. This can include a range of potential work item categories; such as self-healing mechanisms, transparency, automation, and/or increasing the capabilities for Azure Active Directory.

My position is primarily "behind the scenes" providing engineering support to the Worldwide Microsoft Identity Support Teams whom work on Customer Support incidents and require Product Group engagement. At the same time we occasionally engage directly with customers to help facilitate incident resolution as appropriate.

We 'Value' customer feedback, it is you that help us shape the future and ensure that 'Microsoft' deliver to you the service capabilities and features that you want most! so don't keep it to yourself, reach out to us using vast amount of communication channels available to you... and get your voice heard!

Escalation Engineer

November 2013 - November 2015 (2 years 1 month)

At Microsoft I am based in the Cloud Identity & Access Management Team. I work with our largest, most complex customers, as well as medium sized businesses taking escalations from our support teams across the world and work directly with the Microsoft Product Team.

In my role I have to understand at a low-level & troubleshoot Microsoft's latest cloud identity technologies, work with customers be an Escalation point for other Microsoft engineers from around the world, work on mission critical problems for our largest customers, solve complex problems, using advanced troubleshooting and subject matter expertise and drive communications to the customer and account teams during critical situations.

I work closely with Microsoft Product Teams primarily in the Windows and Microsoft Azure as a BETA Engineer working together to improve products and services, enhance customers experience and influence the way the products are designed well before they land in the hands of our customers.

- Microsoft Azure Infrastructure as a Service (laaS)
- Windows Azure Active Directory Microsoft Cloud Platform
- Graph API
- Microsoft Azure Remote App
- Microsoft Office 365 Microsoft Cloud Services [Exchange/SharePoint/Lync]
- Identity Federation Technologies (AD FS, Shibboleth)
- Microsoft Identity Management (ILM, FIIM, MIIS, or PKI) DirSync & FIM
- Identity protocols (i.e. SAML, WS-*, OAUTH)

EduTech Hosting Founder / Technical Lead January 2010 - 2015 (6 years)

EduTech Hosting Provides FREE Fast & Reliable Web Hosting Services. Currently Providing Linux Hosted Web Space.

EduTech Hosting was setup to help out non-profit organizations, charities and people whom were either currently getting a bad service in regards to there web hosted services or/ needed some web space for development or to get a presence on the Internet. The Ethos has always been and will carry on to be that the services are FREE and no costs shall be incurred.

EduGeek.net

Edugeek Moderator / Events Support April 2009 - 2015 (6 years 9 months)

- Moderate EduGeek Forums
- Get Involved and Help other EduGeek Community
- Help support the Events/Conferences

BT Engage IT

Lead Technical Consultant (Microsoft Core Infrastructure & Cloud Services)

September 2012 - November 2013 (1 year 3 months)

I am part of Microsoft Core Infrastructure & Cloud Services Team within Professional Services at BT Engage IT; my position within the company involves working closely with medium, large & enterprise companies implementing and supporting new and upcoming Microsoft Technologies such as Core Server Platform Services, Communication Services, Collaboration Services and Cloud Services (Office 365 & Azure)

I also operate as the Project Technical Lead, Design & Planning Consultant, and host to customer workshops.

Microsoft:

- Microsoft Server 2008/R2/2012
- Microsoft Server Platform Core Services
- Microsoft Exchange Server 2003/2007/2010/2013
- Microsoft Lync Server 2010/2013
- Microsoft Office 365 for Enterprise & Education (including Wave 15)
- Microsoft SQL Server 2008/R2 & 2012
- Microsoft Hyper V
- Microsoft Forefront Threat Management Gateway & Unified Access Gateway
- Microsoft System Centre

Non-Microsoft Products/Services

- Research in Motion: Mobile Voice System
- VMware Technologies

ITEC Intelligent Services
Lead Technical Consultant
November 2011 - September 2012 (11 months)
Reading, UK

- Senior Microsoft Unified Communications Consultant
- RIM MVS Implementation & Support Engineer
- Technical Lead for Corporate Bank VoIP Project
- Technical Lead for Pitney Bowes VoIP Project
- LifeSize Video Conference Engineer

Introducing new and upcoming leading technologies around Unified Communications, Microsoft Lync + Enterprise Voice as well as other Microsoft Products and Services, Audiocodes Mediant VoIP Gateways, Cisco, Cloud Computing, Managed Wireless, Network Security and Storage Solutions to the channel.

TigerTurf UK Ltd
IT Systems Manager
June 2011 - October 2011 (5 months)

I am currently migrating a TenCate subsidiarie to the Global TenCate Network based in The Netherlands. I carry out the following roles and responsibilities. (The contract has now successfully been completed)

- Maintain and Develop Network Infrastructure
- Maintain Relationship with Corporate IT in The Netherlands
- Main IT Contact for End-User Support
- Maintain Company Server/Desktop Infrastructure
- Company IT Policy Management
- Maintain Physical Security Systems
- Manage Internal projects relating to IT
- Training and Development of Employee knowledge
- Company Disaster Recovery Procedures

Computerworld Business Solutions (CBS) Senior Technical Consultant April 2010 - April 2011 (1 year 1 month)

- Telephone / Email End User Support
- Planning and Installation of Small Business Networks
- Business IT Consultancy at End Company Director Level
- IT / Network Management for Businesses (Multi / Monthly Visits)
- Testing / Demonstration / Implementation of New Technologies
- Installation / Configuration of VPN/Firewall/Routing Appliances
- Training End Users / IT Managers on New Software and Services

Bristnall Hall Technology College

IT & Network Support Technician / Virtual Learning Platform Developer March 2008 - March 2010 (2 years 1 month)

I was working voluntary in the school holidays whilst I was going through my secondary education, when I left school I took a year away studying to gain my professional certifications. In June 2008 I went back to my school I worked voluntary as an ICT Technician. In January 2009 the school put me on a Full Time contract as the Virtual Learning Platform Developer and ICT & Network Support Technician. My Primary Role was to assistant the Network Manager looking after the Servers/Network as well as assisting with the implementation of new technologies, Administration and development of the Learning Platform which was based on SharePoint 2007.

- SIMS Server/client upgrades
- Install / Configuration of network hardware (Core & Edge Switches)
- Development and Administration of SharePoint 2007
- Maintaining printers, desktops and laptops, PDA's etc.
- Implementation of New Technologies Including Training
- Migration of Windows Server 2003 to 2008 R2 (Virtual Environment)
- Management & Upgrading SQL Server 2005 Cluster to SQL Server 2008 (MIS Database)
- Implementation of Oracle VDI (Servers & SAN) (Solaris)
- Implementation of VMware ESXI and Hyper-V Cluster

Education

Cisco Networking Academy

Online Degree (Bachelor), CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate), CCNP (Cisco Certified Network Professional) · (2007 - 2009)

Bristnall Hall Technology College

English, Maths, Science, IT, Business Studies · (2002 - 2007)